《哥谭》前情提要
Previously on Gotham...
这是为了雷吉
That's for Reggie.
我不知道你想从布鲁斯少爷这儿得到什么
Now, I don't know what you want with Master Bruce,
但我确定
but I'm certain
没有你  他能过得更好
that his life's gonna be a damn sight better without you in it.
如果你能考虑为我的市长竞选背书
I would be honored if you would consider...
我将不胜荣幸
endorsing me for mayor.
但如果你能向我保证
But if you can give me your word...
承诺我们不用单独面对
we won't have to face it alone...
我就背书你
...you'll have my endorsement.
我已经挺久没有吃过这样一顿饭了
It's-it's been some time since I had a meal like this.
你该经常过来
You should come over more often.
我们可以一起玩玩
We can, like, hang out or whatever.
好啊
I'd like that.
放开我  你个怪胎
Let go of me, you freak.
听我说
Listen to me.
我是为你做的
I did it for you.
柯丽丝汀
Kristen?
我一直在关注韦恩集团的动向
I've been following the goings-on at Wayne Enterprises.
你都发现了什么
What have you learned?
你父亲是个好人
That your father was a good man.
尽管如此
But in spite of that,
他公司里还是有坏事发生
bad things happened at his company.
你是在找企鹅的母亲吧
Looking for Penguin's mother, weren't you?
他说什么  我就得做什么
I have to obey him in all things.
企鹅给这个可怜人洗脑了
Penguin has brainwashed this poor soul.
能帮他吗
Can we help?
你们俩慢慢玩吧
I'll leave you two to it.
克里尔神父
Father Creel.
你抓到韦恩家的男孩了吗
You have the Wayne boy?
还没呢  但快了
Not yet. But soon.
我找到你母亲了
I found your mother.
-在哪  -码头的一间仓库
- Where? - In a warehouse down by the port.
本字幕由ZiMuZu原创翻译  最新下载请登录www.ZiMuZu.tv
翻译 小胖纸Amy   艾瑞卡   辰星晓Reginamoon   木浅
翻译 盐湖凉开水   大K   小十三   DustD   小酸奶!   草草
时间轴 风吹来的那片云
你确定这里就是吗
You sure this is it?
我确定  老大
I'm sure, boss.
后期 宝宝   校对 草草   总监 草草
我母亲一旦安全了
Once my mother is safe,
我们就去找盖勒文和他妹妹算账
we go after Galavan and his sister.
他们要为自己的所作所为付出代价
They're gonna pay for what they've done.
母亲
Mother!
Mother.
你还好吗
You're okay.
谢天谢地
Thank God.
奥斯瓦尔德
Oswald?
真的是你吗
Is that really you?
你可爱的小脸蛋儿
Your sweet face.
像是幻觉一般
Like a vision.
我带你回家  好吗
I'm taking you home, okay?
我还以为
And there I was,
你知道什么是后果呢
thinking you understood the meaning of consequences.
后果吗  当然
Consequences, yes.
我向你保证
I assure you
等我救出母亲后
that my understanding of consequences
会让你明白我对后果的理解的
will be made quite clear once my mother is outside.
但我们在一起很开心啊
But we've had so much fun together.
我妹妹对她的玩物总会产生依恋
My sister gets attached to her playthings,
所以我得坚持她留在这里
so I must insist she stay.
那断线钳根本毫无用处
And those bolt cutters are useless.
想要出去就只有靠这个
The only way out of there is with this.
好吧
Very well.
布奇
Butch?
朝他们脑袋开枪  然后去抢钥匙
Shoot them both in the head and grab the key.
奥斯瓦尔德
Oswald?
我很抱歉  母亲
Mother, I'm sorry,
但他们对你做的事我无法忍受
but what they've done to you will not stand!
我命令你
I gave you an order!
朝他们脑袋开枪
Shoot them both in the head.
不
No.
不不不  那不可能
No, no, no, that's not possible.
你必须服从我
You have to obey me.
你必须
You have to!
那已经是过去了
That time has passed.
他们把我治好了
They fixed me.
塔比很了解洗脑程序
Tabby is well-versed in the protocols of conditioning.
过程中总会设置个触发词
There's always a trigger word implanted during the process.
我只需让布奇记起那是什么
All I had to do was get Butch remember what it is.
我承认  花了不少功夫
I'll admit, it took a few tries.
但还是成功了
And now here we are.
求你们
Please.
我还有利用价值
I can still be valuable.
你会发现的
You'll see.
真希望是如此
I so wish that were true.
杀我可以  放她走吧
Then kill me if you must, but let her go.
我求你了
I'm begging you.
看着不像求人的态度啊
Doesn't look like begging to me.
是呢  一点都不诚恳
Indeed, half-hearted at best.
拜托
Please.
让我做什么都行
I'll do anything.
看来她已经起到作用了
Perhaps she has served her purpose.
别噘嘴
Don't pout.
你还有个前市长
You still have the former mayor.
他好无聊
He's so dull.
老是哼哼唧唧的
He just moans all the time.
我跟你说了会没事的
I told you everything would be okay.
不是吗
Didn't I?
会没事的
And it will be.
不
No!
奥斯瓦尔德
Oswald?
出什么事了
What is wrong?
你看起来好难过
You look so sad.
没事  母亲
Nothing's wrong, mother.
什么事都没有
Nothing at all.
我们现在在一起了
We're together now.
这是最重要的
That's all that matters.
只有这个最重要  不是吗
That's all that ever mattered, right?
从你还是个小婴儿时就一直如此
Ever since... you were just a little baby.
我的小科波特
My little Cobblepot.
对不起
I'm sorry.
都是我的错
This is my fault.
请原谅我
Please forgive me.
我真的很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
抱歉什么
For what?
你一直都是个好孩子
You were always such a good boy.
不  不要
No, no.
杀了他
Kill him.
把尸体扔了...
Dump the bodies...
随便扔在哪
anywhere.
你没胆子自己动手杀了我吗
You don't have the stomach to kill me yourself?
怪不得你们家族被赶出城了
No wonder your family was run out of town.
你们家都是一群孬种
You come from a long line of cowards!
好吧  好吧
Fine, fine.
有什么遗言吗
Any last words?
有
Yes.
我会杀了你的
I'm going to kill you.
哥谭
第二季  第七集
你是个变态
You are a psychopath!
我并不是你想的那样
I am not the man you think I am!
我绝不会伤害你的
I would never do anything to hurt you.
起床啦
Rise and shine.
你在这里干什么
What are you doing here?
我把你永远驱逐了
I banished you for good.
差一点吧  因为一个好女人的爱什么的
Almost. Love of a good woman and all of that.
但是  我们都知道最终结果如何  啧啧
Though, we both know how that turned out. Yikes.
那是个意外
That was an accident.
那不是我
I'm not that man.
我要弥补这件事
I'm gonna make this right.
你瞧  我就知道你会这样哭哭啼啼地醒来
See, I knew you'd wake up all boo-hooey.
你八成有一半心思想去自首
You probably have half a mind to turn yourself in.
幸运的是  我掌握了另一半
Luckily, I have the other half.
你喜欢变戏法吗
Do you like magic tricks?
什么
What?
你当然喜欢变戏法啦
Of course you like magic tricks.
毕竟  我喜欢
After all, I do.
你猜怎么着
Well, guess what?
我可以把尸体变不见哦
I can make a body disappear.
她在哪
Where is she?
柯林格小姐的尸体在哪
Where is Ms. Kringle's body?
把信封打开
Open the envelope.
"我趁你睡觉时把她的尸体藏起来了
"I hid her body while you were catching some Zs,
你会需要人搭把手
You'll need a helping hand,
去哥谭市警局找她的名字缩写吧"
so look for her initials down at the GCPD."
你昨晚去了我上班的地方
You went to my work last night?
准确地说  去的是你
Well, technically, you did.
我只负责驾驭你
I was just in the driver's seat,
-可以这么说吧  -怎么可能
- so to speak. - How?
你只是我想象出来的人物
You're a figment of my imagination.
我神经冲动的投射
A projection of impulse.
仅此而已
Nothing more.
你这么说太伤人了
That is uncalled for.
伤人
Uncalled for?
你趁我睡着时劫持了我的身体
You hijacked my body while I was asleep
还偷走了我死去的女朋友
and you stole my dead girlfriend.
好吧
Okay.
是  这倒是真的
Yeah, that's true.
但是我这么做都是为了你好
But I'm doing this for your own good.
我要是你  而且  我其实就是你
If I was you-- which, again, I sort of am--
就赶紧行动
I'd get cracking.
你想第一个发现尸体吧
You do want to find the body first, right?
市政厅现场直播
Reporting live from city hall,
庆祝选举新市长
as we celebrate the latest mayoral election.
投票后民调确认哥谭市的新市长
Early exit polling confirmed that Gotham City's new mayor
将是西奥·盖勒文
will be Theo Galavan,
他预计会以压倒性优势胜出
who is projected to win in a landslide,
且有多名杰出市民为其背书
helped by the endorsement of many prominent citizens,
其中包括警察工会主席詹姆斯·戈登
including police union president James Gordon,
审计长埃德温...
city controller Edwin...
真不敢相信你要当这个阴沟的市长
I can't believe you're gonna be mayor of this sinkhole.
今晚我能去参加庆功宴吗
Can I go to the victory party tonight?
你保证说有我玩的
You promised me fun.
我们什么时候才能大闹一场
When are we gonna unleash a little hell?
想闹  想派对  回头有的是时间
There'll be plenty of time for unleashing hell and parties
只等布鲁斯·韦恩把他的公司转让给我
once Bruce Wayne has signed over his company
并迎来他的不幸命运
and met his unfortunate destiny.
在那之前
Until then,
我还不能松懈
I need focus.
小布鲁斯可越来越喜欢你了
Young Bruce has become fond of you.
到时候他对你的信任将十分关键
His trust will be crucial when the time comes.
我需要你确保
I need you to ensure
没有别人能对他吹耳边风
that no one else is whispering in his ear
直到我提出提议
until I make my offer.
看到这根手指了吗
See this finger?
我手指一勾  小布鲁斯就会跟我走
I've got little Bruce wrapped tight around it.
你真出落成个小狐狸精了
What a vixen you've become.
我好为你骄傲
You make me very proud.
我们还有企鹅要对付
And we have Penguin to deal with.
-我来对付他  -不
- I'm on it. - No.
我就要当上市长了
I'm about to become mayor.
我会有自己的人马可以差遣了
I'm gonna have an army at my disposal.
该派他们上场了
Time to use it.
看来你支持对了人
Looks like you backed the right horse.
你信任他吗
You trust him?
一个哥谭的政客吗
A Gotham politician?
我才不信任他呢
About as far as I can throw him.
但如果他能满足哥谭市警局的需求
But if he gives the GCPD what it needs,
我就不介意
he's all right by me.
你知道吗  塞琳娜说企鹅是
You know, Selina said Penguin
韦恩集团纵火案的主使者
was behind the Wayne Enterprise fires.
所以呢
So?
他先是追杀市长候选人
First he's going after mayoral candidates,
接下来又去烧大楼
next thing you know, he's burning down buildings.
这说不通啊
Doesn't make any sense.
那人就是个大写的疯子
Guy is an abacus of crazy.
他做出什么事都不会让我吃惊
Nothing he does surprises me.
发生什么事了
What the hell happened?
是企鹅
Penguin.
他企图杀我们的下任市长
He tried to kill our next mayor.
科波特先生知道我今天必将赢得选举
Mr. Cobblepot knew that I was poised to win the election today,
所以他来找我结盟
and he came to me seeking an alliance.
于是你拒绝了
And you refused.
当然  我礼貌地拒绝了他
I politely declined, yes.
他就捅伤了你的脖子
So he stabbed you in the neck?
即使对于企鹅来说
That seems like a pretty extreme reaction,
这也太极端了吧
even for Penguin.
从我来到这里
We've been trying to build a case
我们就一直在筹备立案起诉企鹅
against Penguin since I got here.
我们认为他还策划了
We assume that he's behind
此前对其他候选人的袭击
the earlier attacks on the other candidates as well.
而这是他第二次想杀我了
And this is the second time he's tried to kill me.
他是个危险人物
The man is a menace.
而我也十分想把他抓起来
And one that I fully intend to put behind bars.
你是给我准备了什么吧
I assume you have something for me?
对奥斯瓦尔德·科波特的逮捕令
Arrest warrant for Oswald Cobblepot
并搜查扣押其名下
as well as search and seizures
和其合伙人名下的所有财产
on all his properties and known associates.
单子还真长
Quite a list.
我们这就处理
We'll get right on it.
还有别的吗
Anything else?
还有  鉴于最近发生的事件
Yes. In lieu of recent events,
腾博法官宣布进入紧急状态
Judge Turnball has declared a state of emergency
并授予市长办公室额外的权力
and granted the mayor's office additional powers.
这到底是什么意思
Meaning what, exactly?
我一上任就会实施宵禁
The moment I'm sworn in, I'm implementing a curfew
我要命令你的突击队
and I'm ordering your Strike Force
开始挨家挨户地搜查
to begin door-to-door searches
直到抓到科波特先生为止
until Mr. Cobblepot is apprehended.
你是说要下达戒严令吗
You're talking about martial law?
我们是说要将一名危险逃犯绳之以法
We're talking about bringing a dangerous fugitive to justice.
我们会在职权范围内行事
We'll be acting within our legal rights.
没错吧  丹特先生
Am I right, Mr. Dent?
当然了
Absolutely.
我会全力支持你  先生
You'll have our full support, sir.
谢谢你  警监
Thank you, Captain.
戈登警探
Detective Gordon?
你看上去...
You seem...
有点犹豫
hesitant.
谨慎而已
Cautious.
是你跟我说应该
You told me we needed to use
想尽一切可用办法抓捕企鹅这种人
every method at our disposal to go after men like Penguin.
这种人不遵守规则
Men who don't play by the rules.
危急时刻就该采取强势措施
Desperate times call for a strong measure.
我对动用一切力量抓捕企鹅没有意见
I have no problem going after Penguin with everything we've got,
但如果我们要踢开每户普通市民的房门
but if we start kicking down the doors of average citizens
用恐惧维护治安  那我们也比他强不了多少
and policing through fear, we're no better than he is.
还得让人民信任我们啊
People still need to trust us.
他们会的
And they will.
因为到头来
Because at the end of the day,
人民只想有安全感
all people want is to feel safe.
记住  警探
Just remember, Detective.
是你来找我的
You came to me.
西奥·盖勒文将担任哥谭市长
Theo Galavan will be the mayor of Gotham.
民众聚集在外面  气氛相当热烈
A crowd has gathered outside, and the excitement is brimming,
稍后
and in just a moment,
我们将采访一些拥护者
we'll also be talking to many of the supporters
他们奉献了时间与精力来支持...
that gave up their time and effort to support...
正门怎么得罪你了
What do you have against the front door?
没有啊
Nothing.
我就是不喜欢那个
It's the ape who opens it
负责开门的猿人
who I could live without.
我有一个月没见着你了
I haven't seen you in a month.
塞琳娜  你来这里干什么
Selina, what are you doing here?
我这周的经历  说出来你都不信
You wouldn't believe the week I've had.
我有个朋友  布莉姬特
This friend of mine, Bridgit,
决定做一件防火服
decided to build this fire suit.
塞琳娜
Selina...
有些人就是不...
Some people just don't...
这是谁的
Whose is that?
抱歉  我回来时走错了...
Sorry. I got lost on the way back from...
你好
Hello.
茜尔薇·圣克劳德  这是我朋友塞琳娜
Silver St. Cloud, this is my friend Selina.
塞琳娜  这是茜尔薇
Selina, this is Silver.
很高兴认识你
Nice to meet you.
我也是
You, too.
你留下来吃午餐吗
Are you staying for lunch?
-不  -拜托留下来吧
- No. - Please say you are.
我刚搬过来  不认识几个人
I just moved here and don't know many people.
布鲁斯  去让阿尔弗雷德添套餐具
Bruce, go tell Alfred to set another place for lunch.
去吧  肯定很有趣
Come on, it'll be fun!
走  去吧
Go. Shoo.
就剩我们两个女孩了
While it's just us girls,
我给你点小小建议
let me give you a little advice.
你要再敢来这里
You come around here again...
你的下场
Well, that would be bad.
会很惨
For you.
你是谁啊
Who the hell are you?
我是布鲁斯的朋友
I'm Bruce's friend.
他唯一的朋友
His only friend.
而你就是个下贱胚子
And you're a piece of gutter trash.
问你个事
Now, tell me something,
如果有一天你消失不见了  会有人...
would anyone miss you if one day you were just...
想你吗
gone?
我猜也没有
I didn't think so.
我跟阿尔弗雷德说了
I told Alfred.
你们在说什么
What are you guys talking about?
没什么
Nothing.
女生之间的事而已
Just girl stuff.
你会需要人搭把手
"...you'll need a helping hand.
去哥谭市警局找她的名字缩写吧
Look for her initials down at the GCPD."
"Look for her initials down at the GCPD"?
去哥谭市警局找她的名字缩写吧
"Look for her initials down at the GCPD."
柯丽丝汀·柯林格  K.K.
Kristen Kringle. K.K.
K.K.
K.K.  K.K.  K.K.
K.K., k.K., k.K.
詹妮弗·金姆
贾斯廷·克龙
凯莉·格林
基思·亚当斯
基思·卡利法诺
失踪  凯尔·戴维斯
别啊
No.
快点
Come on.
迈克  能来帮把手吗
Hey, Mike, can you give me a hand with this?
让哥谭市警局盯上企鹅
Putting Penguin in the crosshairs of the GCPD
会迫使他转战地下
will drive him underground.
如果我们找不到他就杀不了他
We can't kill him if we can't find him.
我们不需要找到他
We won't have to find him.
他会自己送上门
He's going to deliver himself to us.
他为什么要那么做
And why would he do that?
企鹅会被愤怒蒙蔽
Penguin's rage will consume his better judgment,
一心只渴求复仇
leaving him with an insatiable craving for revenge.
我们只需让他继续饥渴
All we need to do is keep him hungry
然后请他来进晚餐
and invite him to dinner.
然后我就可以杀他了吗
And then I get to kill him?
是的  小猫咪
Yes, kitten.
然后你就可以杀了他
Then you get to kill him.
首先  我想感谢全市人民
First, I would like to thank this city
对我的深深信任
for the immense trust it has placed in me.
我很想尽快着手工作
I'm eager to get to work.
另外我想谈谈  一个被称为企鹅的人
I'd also like to address the recent attempt on my life
最近企图谋害我一事
by the man known as Penguin.
的确  他袭击了我
It is true that he attacked me,
而且现在仍在逃逸
and as of now, he is still at large.
我们将不再容忍企鹅之流
Men such as Penguin will no longer be tolerated.
这种人毫无正义廉耻之心
These are men who scurry from the light of decency
就像蟑螂一样
like cockroaches.
这种人  连他妈都不爱他
Men who... not even a mother could love.
他得死
He dies.
就今晚
Tonight.
好的  知道了
Yeah. Got it.
吉尔兹在市中心的一间酒吧里
Gilzean's holed up in a booze joint downtown.
企鹅呢
Penguin?
还有呢  街上有传言
And get this. Word on the street
吉尔兹自己组建了队伍
is Gilzean's started his own crew.
听起来他们俩闹掰了
Sounds like they had a falling out.
也许他愿意谈谈了
Maybe he's ready to talk.
是啊
Yeah.
我听说咱们新市长的事了
I heard about what happened to our new mayor.
真是一刻不得闲啊
Never a dull moment, huh?
可不是
No kidding.
你今早又忘拿钥匙了
You left your keys again this morning.
谢谢
Thank you.
这是开哪的
What's this one?
我公寓的钥匙
A key to my apartment.
我去车里等
I'll be in the car.
怎么了  只是枚钥匙而已
What? It's just a key.
是啊  不是...
Yeah, no, uh...
你想要我那儿的钥匙吗
Do you want a key to my place?
一点也不想要
Not even a little bit.
等下  你有住的地方吗
Wait. Do you have a place?
好像有的
I think so.
抱歉  我有点措手不及
Sorry. Caught me off guard.
我确实大部分时间都在你那里过夜
I guess I do spend most nights there.
这我挺喜欢的
Which I love.
我不喜欢的是凌晨两点被吵醒
What I don't love is hauling ass out of bed at 2:00 a.m.
给做完监视回来  一身辣热狗味的你开门
when you come home from a stakeout smelling of chili dogs.
我就喜欢看你不自在的样子
I love to watch you squirm.
我没有啦
I was not squirming.
有一点点
Little squirm.
我不知道咱们今天要待客  布鲁斯少爷
I had no idea we were entertaining today, Master Bruce.
还会有别人来吗
Anyone else popping by?
不会的  谢谢  阿尔弗雷德
No. Thank you, Alfred.
这真太香了  阿尔弗雷德
This is marvelous, Alfred.
我住在福建时就喜欢上了正山小种
I fell in love with Lapsang souchong when I lived in Fujian.
驱车经过五邑侨乡
Driving through the Wuyi region,
扑面而来的都是用雪松木熏制茶叶的味儿
all you could smell is the burning cedar they use to smoke leaves.
嗯  严格来说应该是松木  小姐
Right, well, technically it's, uh, pinewood, miss,
但很高兴你能喜欢
but I appreciate the enthusiasm.
这气味真是呼人一脸呢  是吧  阿尔弗雷德
That smell really does slap you in the face, doesn't it, Alfred?
那么  塞琳娜
So, Selina?
跟我说说你自己
Tell me about yourself.
有家人吗
Any family?
你真信她这一套吗
You really buying her act?
你说什么
I beg your pardon?
我问你一个问题
Let me ask you a question.
你做两面贱婊有多久了
How long have you been a two-faced slut?
塞琳娜
Selina!
不  说真的  你想要什么
No, seriously, what're you after?
是钱吧
It's the money, right?
肯定不是他诡异的幽默感
I mean it's not his wacky sense of humor.
我觉得我该走了
I think I should go.
不  等等
No, wait.
那是眼泪吗
Is that a tear?
你真厉害
You're good.
不好意思
I'm sorry.
再见  布鲁斯
Good-bye, Bruce.
茜尔薇
Silver.
你刚刚做了什么
What did you just do?!
我知道你看人
I know you're not the best judge
怎么说呢  不怎么准
of, like, you know, people,
但那个女孩不是什么好东西
but that girl is bad news.
我刚帮了你个忙呢
I just did you a favor.
请你离开
I want you to leave.
好啊
Fine.
随便你
Whatever.
也许你说得没错
Maybe you're right.
也许我看人的确不准
Maybe I'm not the best judge of people.
因为一直以来  我都以为你是我的朋友
Because all this time, I thought you were my friend.
但显然  你根本不知道那是什么意思
But clearly, you have no idea what that means.
"我厌倦了隐藏  想获得自由
"I'm tired of hiding and want to be free.
想找到她的尸体
To locate her body,
就找到我缺失的两样东西"
find the two things missing from me."
我们后脑勺的样子挺滑稽的
The back of our head kind of looks funny.
像铅笔头似的
It's like the top of a pencil.
你为什么要这么做
Why are you doing this?
因为  好玩
Because... it's fun!
而且对你有益
And it's good for you.
受折磨怎么就对我有益了
How is it good for me to be tortured?
我简直要被逼疯了
To be driven insane!
我想让你看到  你是谁
I'm trying to show you who you are.
你还不明白吗
How have you not realized that yet?
不过  老实说
Though, to be honest,
你居然还没猜出这道谜语  我挺意外
I'm surprised you haven't figured out this riddle yet.
我是不是该弄得简单些
Should I have made it easier?
或许先试试修改语法错误吧
You could start by using proper grammar.
一句话结尾处的句号是...
A period at the end of a sentence is...
"找到我缺失的两样东西"
"Find the two things missing from ME..."
M句号  E句号
M, period, E, period.
天呐
Oh, God.
M.E.  法医
M.E.-- medical examiner.
你不是吧
You didn't!
是的
I did.
我们等等看有没有人能带我们进去
I say we wait and see if someone can walk us inside.
尽量维持客气的气氛
Try and keep things civil.
我跟你说过我在考虑养猫的事吗
Did I tell you I was thinking about getting a cat?
什么
What?
回过神来了
How are you?
能不能集中点精神
Why don't you get your head in the game here?
抱歉
I'm sorry.
就是
It's just...
你相信盖勒文的说法吗
Do you believe Galavan's story?
这种问题超出我的过问范围
Questions like that are above my pay grade
不在我的好奇范围内
and below my sense of wonder.
企鹅是个实用主义者
Penguin's a pragmatist.
因为他不肯结盟就袭击盖勒文
Hitting Galavan for refusing an alliance?
这对他毫无好处  只会招来麻烦
That doesn't get him anything but heat.
那你觉得究竟是怎么回事
So, what really happened do you think?
几个月前  盖勒文还是无名小卒  是吧
A few months ago, nobody knew who Galavan was, right?
现在  他突然就当上了市长
Now, all of a sudden, he's mayor?
这种事不会是偶然的
Doesn't happen by accident.
这是需要谋划的
It takes planning.
需要帮手
And it takes help.
盖勒文这种人胎投的好
Guys like Galavan are born on third base.
能有作为也算天赋权利了
Stealing home's practically a birthright.
想想这时机
Think about the timing.
他正好在詹姆斯市长失踪后出现
He shows up just after Mayor James disappears.
晚会的屠杀把他塑造成了英雄
The massacre at the gala turns him into a hero.
企鹅对市长候选人的刺杀
Penguin's assassination attempts on mayoral candidates
启动了他的竞选
launched his campaign.
到目前为止发生的一切
Everything that's gone down up to this point,
都可能是精心策划的
you could argue was orchestrated.
你所说的简直疯狂到大师级别
Look, what you're talking about is Machiavellian-level crazy,
哪怕是就哥谭的标准来看
even by Gotham standards.
是啊
Yeah.
我们的门卡来了
There's our door pass.
你妈妈告诉你的
Yeah, so your mother tells you.
他妈妈好几年前就不跟他说话了
Yeah, his mama stopped talking to him ages ago.
可来了
Oh, finally.
别
I wouldn't!
拜托
Aw, come on.
真劝你别
I really wouldn't.
火力挺强啊  布奇
That's a lot of firepower there, Butch.
等人呢吗
You expecting company?
这街区不如往日了  吉姆
Neighborhood ain't what it used to be, Jim.
企鹅呢
Where's Penguin?
我怎么知道
How should I know?
你不是他的走狗吗  会不知道主人在哪
You're the boss' lapdog and you don't know where your owner is?
我不是任何人的走狗
I ain't nobody's lapdog.
再也不是了
Not anymore.
证明给我们看
Prove it.
告诉我们企鹅为什么要袭击盖勒文
Tell us why the hell Penguin went after Galavan.
我什么都不会告诉你的
I ain't telling you anything.
除非你有逮捕令
And unless you have a warrant,
我得请你们离开了
I'm gonna have to ask you boys to leave.
嗯  问题是
Yeah, see the thing is
我们新当选的市长要我们拿出结果
our newly elected mayor kind of wants results on this.
我们如果把你带回警局  你估计就别想出来了
So we drag you in, chances are that's where you're gonna stay.
我来找吉尔兹
I'm here for Gilzean!
现在走的  饶你们不死
Anyone who leaves now leaves alive.
现在不走
Anyone who stays
小命不保
dies!
给你们60秒钟考虑
You have 60 seconds to do the math.
抱歉  布奇
Sorry, Butch.
不是吧
Seriously?
坏蛋不讲义气啊
No honor among scumbags, huh?
别开枪  我就走
Hey, don't shoot! I'm out of here!
你干什么
What are you doing?
告诉我们企鹅究竟怎么回事
You tell us what the hell's going on with Penguin
否则我们就把你留给萨斯
or we leave you with Zsasz.
你不能那么做
You can't do that.
-布洛克  -绝对可以
- Bullock? - We can totally do that.
是盖勒文在指使企鹅
Galavan was telling Penguin what to do.
让他杀候选人  烧楼
Knocking off the candidates, torching the buildings--
都是盖勒文下的命令
it all came down from Galavan.
那企鹅为什么要听他的
Why the hell was Penguin taking orders?
他绑架了企鹅的母亲
Kidnapped Penguin's mother.
一直扣着她当筹码
He was keeping her for leverage.
绑架
"Kidnapped"?
吉姆
Jim?
我们得走了
I think we need to go.
我没想到盖勒文真会那么做
I didn't think Galavan actually go through with it.
真会怎么做
Go through with what?
Go through with what?!
哥谭市警局  放下武器
GCPD! Put down your weapons!
我们人手严重不足啊  搭档
We're outmanned here big time, partner.
是啊
Yeah.
但火力可充足
But not out-gunned.
可不是
Oh, hell yeah.
我就当你不肯出来了
I'll take that as a no!
回见  布奇
See you later, Butch!
这可没见过
That's a new one.
你觉得他说的是实话吗
You think he was telling the truth?
没人会说实话
Nobody's telling the truth.
这可是哥谭
This is Gotham.
布鲁斯
Bruce.
真是又惊又喜
What a lovely surprise.
你好  先生
Hello, sir.
我是来找茜尔薇的
I was looking for Silver.
她在的
She's here.
她回来时似乎有点沮丧
Seemed a bit upset when she came in.
是啊  之前茜尔薇来时
Yes, a friend of mine stopped by
我一个朋友来看我了
the house when Silver was there.
她们
They--
不必多说  我也年轻过
Say no more. I was your age once.
你的感情表明了你的人品
Your feelings do you credit.
我从未见过你父亲  但显然
I never met your father, but it's clear
他给你灌输了很正确的道德观
that he instilled in you a sound moral compass.
是啊
He did.
要知道  我们...
You know, we're both...
很相像
very alike.
都是生于贵胄之家
Born into wealth and privilege,
却又被迫过上孤独的生活
yet forced to walk our lives alone.
被丧亲所困扰
Haunted by loss.
一心想向先人证明自己的价值
Driven to prove ourselves worthy to those who came before.
小心  布鲁斯
Be careful, Bruce.
这种思维
That way of thinking--
那种想填补空虚的需求
the need to fill a void--
它能吞噬你
it can consume you.
那感觉会消逝吗
Does it every go away?
不会
No.
但你能找到释怀
But you can find closure;
可以向前看  但又不必放弃
a way to move on without letting go.
怎么做
How?
这个嘛
Well...
我不想乱做承诺
I don't want to make any promises,
但等时机到了
but when the time is right,
我们会再谈的
we'll talk again.
我得去为派对做准备了
I, uh, need to get ready for the party.
失陪
Excuse me.
我就知道你会来的
I knew you'd come.
盖勒文的命是我的
No one's to kill Galavan but me.
懂了吗
Understand?
老大  我理解你的感受
Boss, I get what you're feeling.
母爱  那是最美的
Mother's love-- it's the most beautiful,
-最纯粹的  -盖布
- most simple-- - Gabe!
警察绝不会允许你接近盖勒文的
Cops aren't gonna let you within a hundred feet of Galavan.
让我们替你杀了他吧  拜托
Let us whack him for you, please?
不行
No.
他是我的
He's mine.
好了  我们装扮一下吧
Now, let's get dressed.
还得去出席派对呢
We've got a party to attend.
听好了  各位
Listen up, people!
我们新当选的市长将于今晚
Our newly elected mayor is going ahead
举行获胜庆典
with his victory celebration tonight.
他会暴露于公共场合
He will be exposed.
他会容易遭到攻击
He will be vulnerable.
他也会受到保护
And he will be protected.
受你们保护
By you.
本警局勇敢的男男女女
The brave men and women of this police force.
你们都了解自己的任务
You all have your assignments.
戈登警探将负责这次行动
Detective Gordon here will be running point.
警探
Detective?
企鹅今天已经曾试图行刺过盖勒文了
Penguin has already made one attempt on Galavan's life today.
我们要做好一切准备
We should be ready for anything.
让哥谭看到警察的担当吧
Let's show this city what it means to carry a badge.
继续准备
As you were.
周边小队每五分钟汇报一次
I want check-ins from perimeter teams every five minutes.
马丁纳兹  大道情况
Martinez, how's the avenue looking?
安全
All clear.
狙击A队和B队也报告安全
Sniper Teams Alpha and Bravo report all clear as well.
收到
Copy that.
有什么发现
What you find out?
我问过格特鲁德·科波特大楼的楼管
Spoke to the super at Gertrude Cobblepot's building.
据说已经有两周没人见过她了
Turns out, no one's seen her for two weeks.
这与吉尔兹的故事相符
Timeline matches Gilzean's story.
或许那老太太去坐巡游船了呢
Maybe or maybe the old broad's on a sunset cruise, hmm?
吉尔兹的一句话我一直忘不掉
You know, there's something that Gilzean said that I can't shake.
他说他没想到盖勒文真会那么做
He said he never thought Galavan would go through with it.
真会做什么
Go through with what?
我觉得格特鲁德·科波特应该不是去坐巡游船了
I don't think Gertrude Cobblepot is on a cruise.
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
容我首次向各位正式介绍尊敬的
let me be the first to officially introduce you to the honorable
哥谭新市长  西奥·盖勒文
Theo Galavan, the new mayor of Gotham!
法医实验室
爱德
Ed?
你做什么呢
What are you doing?
汤普金斯医生  你好啊
Dr. Thompkins, hello.
我就是...
Uh, I'm just...
在复查我一桩无名女尸案的笔记
double-checking notes for a Jane Doe case I'm working.
需要帮助吗
Do you need help?
不不  她是死透透了
No! No, no, no. She's all gone.
我是说...抱歉
Or she's-- I'm sorry, I'm--
我查好我的笔记了
I'm all done with checking my notes.
笔记在哪
Uh, what notes?
都记在这里呢
It's all up here.
你发现了吗
Do you realize that
只需对案卷采用简单的助忆术
by assigning simple mnemonic devices to case files,
就可以产生
you can produce recall capacity
近乎过目不忘的效果
equal to that of photographic or even eidetic memory?
-爱德  怎么回事啊  -没事
- Ed, what's going on? - Okay.
老实说
Um, truth be told,
我还希望能碰见你呢
I was hoping to run into you here.
单独跟你谈谈
Alone.
是柯林格小姐
It's Miss Kringle.
我们吵了一架
We had a fight.
很遗憾
I'm sorry.
每段关系都会偶尔变得紧张
Every relationship hits a rough patch now and then.
你一直对我们很支持
And you've been so supportive.
不知道我们能不能一起去喝杯咖啡
And I was hoping that maybe we-we could go grab a coffee
你给我点建议
and you could give me some advice.
你要不要先
Uh, do you want to finish up
-完成你的工作  -没事
- what you were doing first? - No, no, no, no.
我可以再找时间来做
I... I can come back another time.
反正尸体也不会起来跑了  是吧
It's not like they're gonna go anywhere, right?
按说是啊
You'd think so.
嗯  好
Yeah, okay.
戈登警探
Detective Gordon.
就这样  先生
That's it, sir.
太好了  多谢
Perfect. Thank you so much.
我听说了今天枪战的事
I, uh, heard about your shoot-out today.
据说是个企鹅之前的副手
Something about one of Penguin's former Lieutenants,
布奇·吉尔兹
a Butch Gilzean?
我们正审问他时遭到了伏击
Some men ambushed us as we were questioning him.
他逃走了
He escaped.
你问出什么来了吗
Did you get anything out of him?
在袭击发生前
Before the attack?
没有
No.
真是可惜
That's a pity.
好了
Well...
警探  有一大群人
Detective, I have a large group of men
从主路旁侧靠近
approaching from off the main road.
我可以看到目标
I have eyes on the target.
应该是科波特  长官
Appears to be Cobblepot, sir.
别开枪
Hold your fire.
周边小队  准备交火
Perimeter units, prepare to engage.
目标被击中
The target is down.
马丁纳兹  我叫你别开火的
Martinez, I said hold your fire.
不是我们
It wasn't us.
屋顶有未知枪手
We have an unknown shooter on the roof.
重复  屋顶有未知枪手
I repeart, we have an unknown shooter on the roof.
马丁纳兹
Martinez.
企鹅死了吗
Is Penguin dead?
-不  那个不是他  -找到另一名狙击手
- No, it wasn't him. - Find the other shooter
找到企鹅  我们得抓活的
and find Penguin-- we need him alive.
警探  所有目标都穿成了企鹅的样子
Detective, all the targets are dressed as Penguin,
而且都持有重武器
and all are heavily armed.
根本无法确认目标
Positive I.D. is impossible.
马丁纳兹  可以开火
Martinez, you're clear to engage.
所有周边小队  立刻赶往我地点
All perimeter units, crash our location now.
放下枪
Drop it.
转过来
Turn around.
手举过头  马上
Hands above your head, now.
真强势
So forceful.
我就喜欢强势自信的男人
I like a strong confident man.
我们得送你出去
We got to get you out of here.
无线电通知他的司机
Radio his driver,
让他把车开到后门服务人员入口
have him pull the car around to the back service entrance.
-知道了吗  -是
- Got it? - Yes.
-掩护我们  -好的
- Cover us? - No problem.
其余警官留在楼内  戒备大堂
Remaining officers stay inside and clear the lobby.
确认  第一队已经在途
Confirmed. Primary is on the move.
启动撤退计划  从南门撤出
Initiating exit plan using the south entrance.
收到  戈登警探带市长
Roger that, Detective Gordon is en route
正前往后门
to the rear entrance with the mayor.
立刻将豪轿开往后门服务人员入口
Need that limo at the back service entrance, stat.
收到
Copy that.
带他走
Get him out of here!
快走
Go!
你好啊  吉姆
Hello, Jim.
请你让开
Please step aside.
你知道我不能那么做
You know I can't do that.
你如果知道你保护的是什么样的人就会让开的
You would if you knew what kind of man you were protecting.
打死他  警探
Shoot him, Detective.
奥斯瓦尔德  听我说
Oswald, listen to me.
你必须放下枪
You have to put the gun down.
他杀了我母亲  吉姆
He killed my mother, Jim.
我知道
I know.
戈登警探  我命令你
Detective Gordon, I am ordering you
干掉他
to put that man down now.
他叫人当着我的面杀了她
He had her murdered in front of me.
我抱着她
I held her.
看着她死去
Watched her die.
你知道那是什么感觉吗
Do you know what that's like?
那会改变一个人
It changes a person.
你母亲的事抱歉了  企鹅
Sorry about your mother, Penguin,
但你得把猎枪放在地上
but I'm gonna need you to put the shotgun down on the ground,
慢慢来
slowly, now.
今晚我们有一个人会死
One of us is gonna die tonight.
我已经接受死亡了
I have made my peace with that.
我建议新市长也接受吧
I suggest the new mayor does as well.
别逼我们冲你开枪
Don't make us shoot you.
打死我  你就别想知道他的盘算了  吉姆
Shoot me and you have no idea what his endgame is, Jim.
你该知道
And you should.
因为那关系到一个你认识的人
Because it concerns someone you know,
你在乎的人
someone you care about.
打死他
Shoot him.
趴下
Down!
吉姆  奥斯瓦尔德
Jim, Oswald!
企鹅开着市长的车冲破了主关卡
Penguin smashed the mayor's ride through the main checkpoint.
好消息是
The good news is--
考虑到他肩上受了枪伤  加上我们发的通告
with the gunshot wound to the shoulder and the APB,
他估计是出不了城的
I doubt he'll make it out of the city.
他不会想出城的
He won't be trying to make it out.
我们今晚又损失了更多人
We lost more people tonight.
好人  包括马丁纳兹
Good people, including Martinez.
好人也有不顺的时候
Sometimes the good guys have a bad night.
这不怪你
This ain't your fault.
我知道
I know.
怪他
It's his.
我的先祖是铸剑者
My ancestors were swordsmiths.
他们知道好钢需要锻造
They knew that to good steel, it had first to be forged.
今晚的事
I look at tonight...
我认为是火的洗礼
I look at tonight as a baptism of fire.
这火将把我们锻造得更加强大
A fire from which we will emerge stronger.
更加坚定
Our resolve forged
为哥谭带来新的一天
to bring about a new day in Gotham.
我搬来之后一直觉得很孤单
I've felt pretty alone since moving here.
直到遇见了你
Until I met you.
但我不希望影响你和你朋友的感情
But I-I don't want to come between you and a friend.
你不会的
You won't.
塞琳娜永远都不会喜欢我的
Selina is never going to like me.
我不管
I don't care.
我喜欢你
I like you.
戈登警探
Detective Gordon.
市长先生
Mr. Mayor.
看到我的讲话了吗
You catch my speech?
我听了不少讲话了
I think I've heard enough speeches.
我本对你寄予厚望
I had high hopes for you.
我以为你敢狠下心  做艰难的决定
I thought you were prepared to make the hard choices,
不惜一切  斩除哥谭的恶魔
to do whatever it takes to rid Gotham of its monsters.
我敢
I am.
我刚刚决定
I've just decided...
就从你下手
I'm gonna start with you.
这种话
Dangerous words...
对如今控制了哥谭的人说有些危险啊
when addressing the man who now controls this city.
危急时刻嘛
Desperate times.
的确是啊
They are, indeed.
我想知道你为什么这么做
I want to know why you did this.
汤普金斯医生走进来时  你什么感觉
When Dr. Thompkins walked in the room, how did it feel?
我吓坏了
I was terrified.
她可能会发现尸体呢
She could have discovered the body.
但她没有
But she didn't.
你没被发现
You got away with it.
那不是重点
That's not the point.
这完全就是重点啊
That is absolutely the point!
你还能感到那股刺激  是吧
You can still feel the rush, can't you?
险些被抓到
Coming so close to getting caught.
心知如果她发现了尸体
Knowing what you would have been forced to do
发现了你做的事
if she had discovered the body,
你将不得不做什么
discovered what you had done.
站在未知的边缘
Standing... standing at the edge of uncertainty
向虚无凝视
and peering into the void.
告诉我  那感觉如何
Now tell me, how did it feel?
很棒
Beautiful.